(ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)＜漆黒の痣に覆われた
メリオダスは➡
Meliodas, covered in jet-black marks,
桁違いの魔力を見せる＞
revealed his staggering power.
A power that surpasses even that of the New Generation: the power of the Demon Clan.
＜ それは
新世代をも凌駕する 魔神の力＞
＜メリオダスは何者なのか＞
Just who exactly is Meliodas?
＜七つの大罪は 本当に敵なのか＞
Are the Seven Deadly Sins really the enemy?
With each of them still sorting through their thoughts, more battles are just on the horizon.
＜ それぞれに去来する思いを胸に
また 新たな戦いが始まる＞
＜残る七つの大罪は…＞
The Sins who have yet to appear are...
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～‼ うぅ…｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)ん？ しっかり｡
(鎧巨人)うぅ…｡
Hold steady.
(鎧巨人･回想)
((ああっ…｡ ぼおぉ～！))
Book...
Read... book...
(鎧巨人)本… 読む…｡
It's not such a good idea to read while you're walking.
(ｱﾗﾝ)歩きながら本を読むと
人の迷惑になりますよ｡➡
Now, let's keep moving.
さあ 歩いて｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)この調子でいけば
夕刻には読めます｡
If you keep up this pace,
we'll be able to read tonight.
(鎧巨人)ゴウセル… うれしい…｡
Gowther... happy...
This is a tale of humans and beings from other worlds.
＜ これは いまだ
人と 人ならざるものの世界が➡
分かたれてはいなかった
古の物語＞
It is a story of ancient times.
Liones wasn't the only nation with the power of the Holy Knights.
＜聖騎士を有する国は
リオネス一国にとどまらず➡
ブリタニア全土に及んだ＞
They are used throughout all Britannia.
Magic is power.
＜魔力は力であり その力こそが➡
And that very power
is what shapes the fate of each nation.
一国の命運をも左右した＞
Amongst the numerous Holy Knights, there is one group whose fame stretched all across Britannia.
＜数ある騎士たちの中で
ブリタニア全土に➡
その名を轟かせた
その者たちの名は…＞
And that group's name was—
're
Those who wander looking for answers, those who question in confusion
samayoi tou mono mo tomadoi kou mono mo
Will go beyond all sin.
subete no tsumi wo koe
Episode 14
A Person Who Reads
Boo!
ここにしましょう｡
Let's rest here.
ぼおぉ～～！➡
おおっ！
(ｱﾗﾝ)あっ 待って！
Wait!
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～！
(ｱﾗﾝ)いた｡
There you are.
少し待っていてくださいね｡
Just wait here for a sec.
Birds are foragers.
(ｱﾗﾝ)鳥は 食料調達
あるいは休むために➡
They'll also gather under trees to rest.
植物のもとへやってきます｡
鳥を呼び寄せるときは➡
When one wishes to attract birds, it's best to rely on nature.
自然の摂理を利用しましょう｡
ん？
僕は 止まり木ではありません｡
I'm not a perch for you to sit on.
餌でもありません｡
I'm not food, either.
Are you laughing?
笑っているのですか？
では 僕も笑いましょう｡
Guess I'll join in on the fun as well.
わ～ははははっ！
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～！
あっ｡
(鎧巨人)あぁ… 怖い…｡
Scared...
それは 野ウサギ｡
君に仇なす者ではありません｡
That's just a hare. Nothing you need to be afraid of.
(鎧巨人)ゴウ… セル… 怖い…｡
Gowther...
Scared...
(ｱﾗﾝ)森に還してきます｡
I'm going back to the forest.
ふむ これなら…｡
This should do.
Yeah.
ぴったりです｡
It's perfect.
あっ｡ やはり
接着剤か何か必要ですね｡➡
Oh.
Looks like we'll need
something to stick it on after all.
雨がやんだら探しに行きます｡
(鎧巨人)うぅ…｡
I'll go take a look once the rain stops.
Rain is one process of circulating water.
雨は 水の循環の一過程です｡➡
地表から蒸発した水は
空気中の塵などを核に 雲を作り➡
Water evaporates from the surface and
condenses into clouds in the atmosphere.
The water then falls back down to the Earth.
降った雨は 地中に染み込み➡
This creates rivers which then flow into oceans before returning to the sky.
川となり 海へ流れ
そして また 天に上ります｡➡
Everything in this world is part of a cycle of life.
この世のものは
なんでも循環しているそうです｡➡
Plants, insects, and animals all eat for the sake of survival.
植物や虫 動物も
生きるために ほかのものを食べ➡
Once they die, they return to the earth.
死んだら 土に還る｡➡
This process of life repeats itself forever and ever.
ぐるぐると絶え間なく
営みは繰り返される｡➡
Those who deviate from this course...
そこから外れた者たちは
どこへ行けばいいのでしょうね｡
I wonder where they should go.
Book...
(鎧巨人)本…｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)そうでした｡
Ah, that's right.
Which book should we read?
どの本にしますか？
｢暗黒の脈動｣➡
Dark Pulsation ?
｢暗闇の記憶｣ ｢彼女の正義｣｡
The Memory in Darkness ?
Or maybe A Young Girl's Justice ?
(鎧巨人)うぅ～｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)君は 本当に➡
That one.
You really love this book, don't you?
この本が好きですね｡➡
Hey, this is a pretty nice arrangement.
あっ ねえ 君！ この状況｡
(鎧巨人)あぁ？
(ｱﾗﾝ)僕が本を読み 君が聞く｡
I read a book while you listen...
I get to learn while you're entertained.
君は喜び 僕は勉強になる｡
We're participating in the cycle of life as well.
僕たちも 循環しているんですよ｡
Something like this wasn't written anywhere.
こんなこと
どこにも書いていなかった｡
It's a discovery!
発見です！
そうですよね｡
でも 魅力的な仮説です｡
Or so I'd like to say.
It's an attractive hypothesis either way.
少なくとも 僕は興味深い｡
At the very least, I'm interested.
ありがとう｡
また一つ 学びました｡➡
Thank you.
I've learned something new again.
君と一緒にいると勉強になります｡
Whenever I'm with you, I'm always learning.
Thank... you...
(鎧巨人)あり… がとう…｡
Yes. Thank you.
はい ｢ありがとう｣です｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)もうすぐ
君との旅が終わるのが残念です｡
I'm sad that our travels together will soon come to an end.
(騎士)ヘルブラム卿！
Master Helbram!
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)何？ 何？ どうしたの？
俺っちたちは休養中よ？
What, what? What do you want?
Can't you see we're taking a break?
(騎士)申し訳ありません｡
バイゼルより東 オーダンの森で➡
My apologies, sir!
However, we have just received a report
that the Armor Giant was sighted in Ordan Forest, east of Byzel.
例の鎧の巨人を発見との
報告がありました｡
Armor Giant? Could it be
one of the remaining Seven?
(ｼﾞｪﾘｺ)鎧の巨人？
まさか 残る七つの大罪の…｡
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)色欲の罪 ゴウセル｡
The Goat's Sin of Lust, Gowther.
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)
ふぅ～… ｢暁闇の咆哮｣を呼べ｡
Summon Dawn Roar.
(２人)あっ｡
(騎士)ヤツらを？ それは…｡
We're going to call them in?
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)今度こそ逃がすな｡
確実にしとめろ｡
Don't let him escape again.
We must ensure he is taken down.
Yes, sir!
(ｼﾞｪﾘｺ)
くそっ！ どうして待機なんだ!?
Dammit! Why are we on standby?
Jericho, can you do something about that tongue of yours?
ジェリコ その言葉遣い
どうにかならないの？
せっかく かわいい格好してるのに｡
服 関係ないだろ！
I mean, you're wearing something cute for once.
My attire has nothing to do with this!
Calling for Dawn Roar is a bit unexpected,
｢暁闇の咆哮｣を差し向けたのは
予想外だけど➡
ヘルブラム卿の考えが
あるのでしょう｡
but I'm sure Master Helbram has it all planned out.
何より
私たちは 七つの大罪に屈した｡➡
Either way, we lost to the
Seven Deadly Sins once before.
So our number one priority is to
become stronger before the next fight.
次の戦いまで
今は 力を付けるべきよ｡
I'll see you around.
それじゃあ｡
おい どこ行くんだ？
Hey, where are you going?
Well, we are on break after all.
せっかくの休暇なので｡
But you just said we should get stronger.
今 力を付けるべきって…｡
ギーラ！
Hey, Guila!
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)おばさん また明日｡
See you tomorrow, Auntie!
I'm home...
≫(ｼﾞｰﾙ)ただいま…｡
おかえり…｡
Welcome back.
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)お姉ちゃん！
おかえり！ お仕事 お疲れさま｡
Sis! Welcome back!
Thanks for always working so hard.
Zeal!
ジール！ その傷は？ 一体誰が…｡
Those wounds...
Who did this?
ごめんなさい… おばさんには➡
Sorry...
I was bringing back this
month's pay from Auntie, but...
ちゃんと
今月のお駄賃もらったんだけど➡
これしか…｡
All that's left is...
ごめんなさい…
私が留守ばかりしてるせいで｡
I'm sorry.
It's because I always leave you home alone.
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)ううん｡
お姉ちゃんは聖騎士だもん｡➡
It's okay, Sis.
You're a Holy Knight. It's to be expected.
忙しくて当然だよ｡ 僕➡
As long as it's for you, I'll endure anything.
お姉ちゃんのためなら
なんだって我慢できる｡➡
Don't work too hard and get sick, okay?
無理して 体を壊さないでね？
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)うん｡
Okay.
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)王国を狙ってる
七つの大罪なんかに負けないでね｡
Don't lose to those Seven Deadly Sins who are after the kingdom, okay?
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)うん｡
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)でも ケガだけはしないでね｡
Okay.
Just... don't get injured yourself, okay?
Does it sting?
しみる？
ううん｡
Nope.
ありがとう お姉ちゃん｡
パリン！
Thanks, Sis!
You disgraces of Holy Knights!
王国聖騎士の面汚し～！
(２人)ははははっ！
聖騎士だった父さんが➡
Everyone says that our father was a Holy Knight who ran away during a mission.
任務の途中で逃げ出して
そのせいで➡
たくさんの人が死んだ
って みんなは言ってる｡
And because of that, many people died.
But I believe...
でも 僕は信じてる｡
父さんは
仲間を見捨てたりなんてしない｡
I know that Father wouldn't abandon his friends!
何か訳があって
帰って来られないだけなんだ｡
I'm sure there was some reason that he couldn't come back.
Sis, you became a Holy Knight because you believed in him as well, right?
お姉ちゃんも
父さんを信じているから➡
聖騎士になろうと
思ったんだよね？
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)少し違うわ｡
えっ？
No, not exactly.
I wanted to protect you in place of Father.
父さんの代わりに
ジールを守りたかったから｡➡
ジールの誇りでいられるような
存在になりたかったから｡
To become someone you could be proud of.
I'm fine, even if I'm by myself.
僕 一人でも 全然平気だよ｡
おばさんのお店で
お手伝いしてるんだもん｡
I'm always helping out at Auntie's store anyway!
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)ジール…｡
Zeal...
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)
｢こうして 父の帰りを信じて➡
And so, the two children went on with their lives,
二人の子供は暮らしたのでした｣｡
believing that their father would return.
また読んであげるわ｡
Next time I'll read to you some more.
ん… お姉ちゃん｡
何？
Sis...
Yes?
やっぱり 短いの気になる？
I knew it. Do the short bangs bother you?
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)ううん｡ すごくかわいいよ｡
No...
I think it's really cute.
もう… ありがとう｡
Thank you.
Hey, why don't we go and throw some more rocks?
なあ また 石 投げに行かねぇ？
Nah, that's too soft.
なまぬるい｡ 次は 火つけようぜ｡
Let's set their house on fire or something!
Isn't that a bit too much?
いくらなんでも
やり過ぎじゃねぇの？
Nah, it'll be fine. Their father
is a traitor to the Holy Knights!
いいんだよ！ あそこのおやじは
裏切り者の聖騎士だ｡
姉貴も 最近
聖騎士になったとかって噂だけど➡
I heard that the sister became a Holy Knight recently as well, but I wonder about her too.
どうだかな｡ はははっ！
And every time that bastard Zeal opens his mouth,
ジールの野郎も
口を開けば お姉ちゃん自慢｡➡
it's always his sister this,
his sister that. It's so damn annoying!
マジで うぜぇんだっつぅの！
What should we do to the midget next?
あのチビ 今度は どんな目に
遭わせてやろっか｡ はははっ！
As long as it's for you, Sis, I'll endure anything.
(ｼﾞｰﾙ)((お姉ちゃんのためなら
なんだって我慢できる))
私もよ｡
Me too.
あなたのためなら
なんでもするわ｡
If it's for your sake, I'll do anything.
(ｼﾞﾘｱﾝ)スレイダー？
Threader?
では 行ってきます｡
静かにしていてくださいよ｡
I'll be heading off now. Please stay quiet, okay?
(鎧巨人)ううぅ…｡
Captain, is this spot okay?
(ﾃﾞｨｱﾝﾇ)団長 この辺でいい？
(ﾒﾘｵﾀﾞｽ)おう｡
Yeah.
村から ちっと離れてるが
呼び込みすりゃあ 平気だろ｡
We're a bit far from the village, but it'll be fine as long as we have some attractions.
Thanks, Mama Hawk!
(ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)ホークママ ありがとう｡
ディアンヌも 少し休んだら？
You should take a break too, Diane.
(ﾃﾞｨｱﾝﾇ)うん｡ じゃあ
お店開ける時間まで寝るね｡
All right, I'll take a nap 'til we open shop then.
ふぁ～… おやすみ｡
Good night!
Now then, let's get ready to open up shop.
さって 開店準備といくか｡
俺たちは 食材調達｡
We'll go gather ingredients.
エリザベスは 村で店の宣伝 頼む｡
Elizabeth, can you do some advertising in the village?
ついでに
ハーブ買ってきてくれるか？
While you're there, can you pick up some herbs?
はい｡
ホーク お前は サポート役だ｡
Sure!
Hawk, you'll be her support.
(ﾎｰｸ)いいけどよぉ
エリザベスちゃんで大丈夫か？
Okay, but are you sure you want Elizabeth to do it?
わ… 私だって
お使いくらいできます！
I-I can handle errands at the very least!
You know you're being targeted by the Holy Knights, right?
いや
聖騎士どもに狙われてんだろ｡
留守番してた方が
いいんじゃねぇか？
Wouldn't it be better just to watch the shop?
あっ…｡
閉じこもってても 滅入るだけだ｡
It's boring to be stuck inside all the time.
大丈夫｡ 何かあったら
すぐ飛んでいくから｡
Don't worry.
If anything happens, I'll be there in a jiffy.
メリオダス様…｡
Lord Meliodas...
けどよぉ…｡
う～ん｡
But still...
Well, what about a disguise?
じゃあ 変装すっか｡
変装？
Disguise?
村娘風！
A village girl!
吟遊詩人風！
A bard!
旅の踊り子風！
A traveling dancer!
That'll make her stand out more!
逆に目立つ！
あの…➡
Um... I think putting on a scarf should be more than enough.
ｽｶｰﾌをかぶるだけで 十分かと…｡
それもそうだな｡
Guess that works too.
さっ 着替え 着替え！
あ… あの…｡
Now, let's change, let's change!
U-Um...
一人で脱げますから！
She can change on her own!
I'm heading off now!
いってきます｡
おう 気をつけろよ｡
Be careful, okay?
(ﾊﾞﾝ)ふぁ～ なんで俺まで…｡
Why do you need me, too?
バン キング
すげぇ獲物 捕まえた方が勝ちな｡
Ban, King, whoever brings back the best catch wins!
Oh? There's no way in hell I'm losing this!
(ﾊﾞﾝ)あん？ ぜってぇ負けねぇ｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)あぁ…｡
ん？ 団長 そういえば 武器は？➡
Captain, what about your weapon?
You're just gonna use your hands?
素手で捕まえる気？
まあ なんとかなるだろ｡
Eh, I'll manage.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)へっ 勝ちはもらったな｡
Hah, then this win's as good as mine!
お前だって 一緒だろ！
Not if I win it first!
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)あんまり暴れないでよ｡
Don't go too crazy, okay?
メリオダス様って➡
I wonder if Lord Meliodas...
has ever had a proper weapon.
ちゃんとした武器
持ったことあるのかしら？
さあな｡ 俺の
知るかぎりでは ないな｡
I dunno.
As far as I know, he hasn't.
I see...
そう…｡ 今まで持っていたのも➡
He's only ever used that
broken sword this entire time.
刃折れの剣だったし
何か理由が…｡
There must be a reason.
エリザベスちゃん 隠れろ！
えっ？
Elizabeth, hide!
Knights... of the kingdom?
王国の騎士…｡
もう嗅ぎつけてきやがった｡
They're hot on our trail already.
(ｱﾗﾝ)ふむ｡ 王国の騎士は
動物並みの嗅覚なのですね｡
So the knights of the kingdom have an animalistic sense of smell, do they?
Well, they can't hold a candle to my nose.
まあ 俺の鼻の方が すごいけどな｡
(ﾎｰｸ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)あっ｡
えっ!?
ほえっ!?
やあ｡ お嬢さんたちも
かくれんぼですか？
Hey, are you two playing hide-and-seek as well?
えっと…｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)失礼しました｡➡
Uh...
My apologies. I should introduce myself first.
まずは挨拶ですね｡
こんにちは お嬢さん｡
Good afternoon, young lady.
こ… こんにちは｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)それから…｡
G-Good afternoon.
And you are...
Oink oink oink!
ブヒブヒ｡ ブ～ ブヒ｡
バカにしてんのか!? プゴッ！
Are you making fun of me?
わあ～！
豚が 人の言葉をしゃべるなんて｡
Whoa, a pig that can talk and understand speech?
あん!?
初めは びっくりしますよね｡
Huh?!
It's a bit of a surprise at first, isn't it?
てめぇも
王国のヤツらに追われてんのか!?
Are you being chased by the kingdom's knights as well?
You too?
｢てめぇも｣？
あなたと一匹もですか？
You and that ?
いちいち むかつくな お前！
ホークちゃん！
You're really starting to piss me off now.
Hawk!
本… 本…➡
Book... Book...
ゴウ… セル… 本 読む…｡
ううぅ…｡➡
Gowther...
Read... book...
どうすか バンさん？ この大物！
How's this, Ban? Check out my huge catch!
The Sword Wolf's lean meat is perfect for smoking!
ソードウルフの肉は
赤身が多くて 燻製にぴったし！
皮も 割といい値で売れる｡
The skin'll get us a nice return too!
Rabbit meat is delicious boiled, stewed, or grilled.
八つ裂きウサギは 煮ても
焼いても ゆでても んまい！
こいつのダシでとるスープは
お肌にいいんだぜぇ｡
Soup made with its meat is great for your skin, too.
Yeah, well, by the rules of the competition, I win.
でも まっ
勝負でいえば 俺の勝ちだろ｡
料理
絶望的 壊滅的味覚オンチが➡
What does a person who's hopeless at cooking with no sense of taste know?
何言ってんだよ｡
キング お前の収穫は どう…｡
King, what'd you catch—
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)くぅ～…｡
(ﾒﾘｵﾀﾞｽ ﾊﾞﾝ)キング！
King!
Take this seriously!
(ﾊﾞﾝ)真面目にやれ！
痛い 痛い 痛い！
Ah, that hurts!
Ban's right! We've gotta stock up to make up for all those days we didn't open up shop!
そうだぞ｡ 商売サボってた分
しっかり仕込みしないと｡
It'll be fine. You guys have caught more than enough.
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)いいじゃないの
二人がとった獲物だけでさ｡
(ﾊﾞﾝ)ダメだ｡ 罰として 俺らより➡
Nope, not at all.
As punishment, you'll have to catch something even better than our kills.
すげぇの捕まえてこい｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)ええ～？
Eh?
Maybe that'll get Diane to see you in a new light, y'know?
そしたら ちょっとは
ディアンヌが見直すかもよ～？
あっ… んんっ！
し… しかたない｡
W-Well, if you insist.
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～…｡
What was that?
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)今の何？ クマや
イノシシじゃなさそうだよね｡
Didn't sound like a wild boar or a bear.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)山の主とかじゃねぇの？
It was probably a mountain god or something.
腹を下したときのホークの
うめき声に めっちゃ似てる｡
It sounded exactly like Hawk's
groaning when he has diarrhea.
ぶっははっ！
痛っ！ 何すんだよ！
Ouch! What the heck was that for?
ちょっと 行ってみっか｡
Guess we should go take a look.
(ｱﾗﾝ)僕は アラン｡
私は…｡
I'm Alan.
I'm—
おい エリザベスちゃん！
お尋ね者が名乗るんじゃねぇ！
Hey, Elizabeth! A wanted person shouldn't carelessly give out her name!
そうね ホークちゃん｡
That's true, Hawk!
So, it's Elizabeth and Hawk.
(ｱﾗﾝ)エリザベスとホークですか｡
(ﾎｰｸ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)あっ…｡
うわぁ～ やっちまった！
Oh, now I've gone and done it. I'm sorry, Elizabeth!
すまねぇ エリザベスちゃん！
ごめんなさい！
I’m sorry too!
Introducing oneself is just etiquette.
名乗り合うのは礼儀です｡
ただ 会話で使うだけですから｡
言い触らしても なんの得にも…｡
We use it for conversation.
There's no point in spreading rumo—
Seems I could make some money with this...
(ｱﾗﾝ)お金が手に入るのですか？
売っ払うなら 俺を売れ～！
If you're gonna sell someone out, sell me!
(ｱﾗﾝ)冗談です｡
あっ｡
I'm just joking.
アランさんは
お金が必要なんですか？
Are you in need of money, Alan?
(ｱﾗﾝ)必要なのは 鎧の接着剤です｡
鎧？
What I'm in need of is some adhesive for my armor.
Armor?
Yes, but I don't think it's
going to help much in the end.
はい｡ でも
本当の助けにはなりません｡➡
苦しんでいる人に
何をしてあげればいいのか➡
I don't know what I should do for someone who is suffering.
分かりません｡
なんと声を掛ければいいのかも➡
Nor what I should say to comfort them.
Or even what expression I should be making.
どんな顔をしていればいいのかも
本には書いていない｡
That's not written in any book.
He's a strange one...
変なヤツ｡
どうしようもないけど➡
We still get anxious even if we can't do anything to help.
いてもたってもいられない気持ち
分かります｡
I know the feeling.
大切な人なら なおさら｡
Especially if that person is important to you.
Important to you?
大切な人？
恋人の方… とかでは？
Like your lover, perhaps?
恋人… 恋する相手｡
Lover... Someone you love...
恋とは 特定の人物に
強く思いを寄せること｡➡
Love is a strong feeling you have for a special someone.
あなたにも そんな相手が？
えっ？
Do you have someone like that?
Huh?
Elizabeth! As long as you're fine, I'm fine too!
((エリザベス
お前が無事なら それでいい))
Don't worry.
((大丈夫｡ 何かあったら
すぐ飛んでいくから))
If anything happens, I'll be there in a jiffy.
あっ…｡ いえ あの…｡
No! It's—
ふむ｡
僕のは それとは違う気がします｡
I don't think this person is really my lover.
そ… そうですか｡
じゃあ ご友人？
I-I see...
Perhaps a close friend?
友人？
それも違うんかい！
Close friend?
That's not it either?
Close friend... Friend...
友人… 友達…｡
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～！
なんだ？
What the?
(騎士)あっ あぁ…｡
おい しっかりしろ！
Hey! Hang in there!
｢暁闇の咆哮｣様たち… が➡
Dawn Roar... is fighting back... against the... Armor Giant...
応戦している…｡
鎧巨人…➡
あっ あっ… 来るな…｡
Get away from me!
鎧の化け物がぁ～！ ぐはっ…｡
You armored monster!
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)鎧巨人？
Armor Giant?
(ﾊﾞﾝ)鎧の化け物って
なんだそりゃ｡
An armored monster? The heck is that?
バン キング 見つけたぞ｡
Ban, King, we've found him.
Huh?
あん？
はっ まさか…｡
You mean...?
ああ｡ ヤツに間違いねぇ｡
Yeah, it's definitely him.
The Goat's Sin, Gowther!
色欲の罪 ゴウセル！
随分と 魔力が はっきり
感じ取れるようになってきた｡
We're able to sense their powers much more clearly now.
近いよ｡
だが 全く動く気配がねぇぜ｡
They're close!
But they don't seem to be moving at all.
どのみち 警戒は怠るなよ｡
Either way, don't let your guard down!
｢暁闇の咆哮｣… 何度か
嫌な噂を耳にしたことがある｡
Dawn Roar... I've heard some nasty rumors about them in the past.
I saw them a few times when I was in the kingdom as well.
おいらも 王国側にいたとき
何度か見かけたよ｡
標的を殺すだけの任務に就く
最悪の戦闘集団だ｡
They're a sinister group of knights that focuses only on killing their target.
かかっ！ 上等だ｡➡
Perfect! That means we can go all out too!
こっちも 遠慮なく好き勝手やれる｡
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～‼
Just as we'd expect.
(ｼﾞﾘｱﾝ)さすがと言うべきか｡
先に送り込んだ騎士団を➡
He was able to annihilate the first group of knights without breaking a sweat.
あっさり全滅させるとは｡
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)全滅させられるザコどもが
ふぬけすぎなんだよ｡➡
No, the scum that got destroyed were just useless.
ねえ スレイダー？
Right, Threader?
Gowther, are you all right?!
ゴウセル 無事か!?
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)スレイダー あいつら…｡
Threader, those guys are—!
There's no need to concern ourselves with that.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)
余計な思考と詮索は不要｡➡
アタシたちの仕事は
粛々と対象を始末することよ｡➡
Our job is simply to assassinate our target with minimal disturbance.
集中しなさい｡
Please focus.
Captain...
団長…｡
動いた方が負ける｡
Whoever moves first, loses.
So this is where you were. Apologies for being late.
(ｱﾗﾝ)ここにいましたか｡
遅くなって すみません｡➡
村を探し回りましたが
接着剤は見つかりませんでした｡➡
I looked all over the village
but couldn't find any adhesive.
ん？ なんですか？
(ﾊﾞﾝ)お前こそ なんだよ!?
What's wrong?
What the hell are you doing?!
Me? I'm—
僕？ 僕は…｡
(鎧巨人)うぅ… 怖い…｡➡
Scared...
Gowther... scared...
ゴウセル… 怖い…｡
(ｱﾗﾝ)君！
(ﾊﾞﾝ)何言ってんだ？
You—!
What are you on about?
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～‼
逃げろ！
Run!
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)殺れ｡
Finish him.
こいつ 強い！ 逃げろ ゴウセル！
This guy is strong!
Run away, Gowther!
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～！
ふっ！
Prepare the next wave!
(ﾋｭｰｺﾞ)第二波 準備｡
(ｼﾞﾘｱﾝ)ヒューゴ 上！
Heads up, Hugo!
(ﾋｭｰｺﾞ)これは…｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)すまないけど➡
This is...
Sorry, but until this is over, I'll keep you as a statue.
事が済むまで
石になっててもらうよ｡
(ﾋｭｰｺﾞ)サイモン｡
ザシュ！
Simon!
What?!
事が済むまで
身悶えしてもらうわ｡
Until this is over, I'll keep you writhing in agony!
Guess it's my turn next!
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)お次は アタシの番よ！
させるか！
Like I'd let you!
Why don't we?
させようよ｡
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～！
ガリガリガリッ！
Thanks for drawing all their attention.
(ﾜｲﾝﾊｲﾄ)
引き付け役 ご苦労さまっす｡
そりゃ無理だ｡ はっ！➡
You wish!
くっ！
(ﾜｲﾝﾊｲﾄ)残念｡➡
An illusion?
Too bad.
充填完了｡➡
Charging complete.
ア～ンド 任務完了｡
And mission complete.
Gowther!
ゴウセル！
(ｱﾗﾝ)何が起こったのか
一同は 全く理解できずにいた｡➡
No one could understand what had just happened.
男は死体のごとく ただ静かに
時を待っていたのだ｡➡
The man was quietly waiting for an opportune moment, hiding amongst the dead bodies,
死角から放たれるであろう
渾身の一矢を｡
knowing that there would be
a decisive attack from the blind spot.
封印を解いた代償は
高くつくぞ 人間｡
The price of releasing this seal will be immense,
human.
Seal, you say?
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)封印… ですって？
おい お前の その口調…｡
Hey, you, that manner of speech...
And that symbol on your chest...
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)その胸元の印… まさか！
Are you—?
Yes. My true identity is...
ああ 俺の正体は…｡
ええ～!?
おいおいお～い｡
Eh?!
Hey, hey, hey...
No way in hell!
ありえねぇ！
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
七つの大罪が一人 色欲の罪➡
A member of the Seven Deadly Sins,
the Sin of Lust.
色欲の罪 ゴウセル｡
The Goat's Sin,
Gowther.
kimi no sonzai dake de sekai wa mangekyou mitai da
With just your presence, the world begins to look like a kaleidoscope.
hashiru kimi ni awase keshiki wa irodzuku kara
The scenery fills with color as you run onward.
hora mata kimi no mae de namida wo miseteshimatta
Here I am, showing you my tears again.
nani ga attemo zutto hanaranaide kureta
But no matter what, you always stay by my side.
dareka wo mamorinuku to dareka ni tsumi wo tsukuru
By protecting someone, you create a sin for someone else.
ikiru hodo ai wo shitte kokoro wa tsuyokunaru
Learn of love, and grow stronger the longer you live on.
me no oku ni utsuru kako no kizu wa
But I'll drink down the scars from your past,
watashi ga nomihosu kara
Reflected in the depths of your eyes.
kimi no sonzai dake de sekai wa mangekyou mitai ni
With just your presence, the world begins to look like a kaleidoscope.
kuru kuru mawatte hikari ga sasu
Spinning around and around, shining its light.
kawaru kisetsu to kawaranai waraigoe
The seasons change while our laughing voices remain the same,
kimi wa omoide ni naranai yo
But you'll never be reduced to a memory,
koko ni iru kara
Because you're right here with me.
Next Episode's Report
A young man calling himself Gowther,
the Goat's Sin from the Seven Deadly Sins appears!
＜七つの大罪 色欲の罪
ゴウセルを名乗る少年が現れた＞
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)ゴウセル 参上｡
お前が ゴウセルなら➡
Gowther has arrived!
If you're really Gowther,
what's with the huge armor?
なぜ
こんな大きな鎧が必要なんだ？
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
古人いわく 大は小を兼ねる｡➡
As the saying goes, better too big than too small.
団長たちも
大きな服を着てみたらどうだ？➡
Why don't you guys try some bigger clothes, too?
少しくらい破けても
気にならなくなるぞ｡
Even if they're a bit torn up, it shouldn't bother you.
なるほど｡
I see.
却下だ！
I refuse!
次回 『七つの大罪』
｢アンホーリィ･ナイト｣｡
Next time, on the Seven
Deadly Sins: "Unholy Knight."
＜ゴウセルの変装には 果たして
意味があったのだろうか？＞
Was there even a reason for Gowther's disguise?
Episode 15
Unholy Knight
先ほど入ったニュースです｡
西アフリカのシエラレオネに滞在
歴のある
東京都内の７０代の女性が今日､
発熱の症状を訴えたため､